Mechanicsville, MD • lanebucklerstu@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/lane-buckler-aa1056158

SUMMARY

Financial professional with a Bachelor's Degree in Accounting and 3 years work experience. Candidate for Bachelor's in Computer Science by August, 2024.

Highly analytical and critical thinker self-propelled in finding the most optimal outside-the-box solutions to technical and creative problems. Able to prioritize, multitask, and adapt quickly while delivering accurate, quality results to team, management and clients. Proclivity for data analysis and decision-making, business and finance, coding and programming, cloud/software engineering, and machine learning.

EXPERIENCE

Junior Financial Analyst | Bowhead | California, MD | October 2022 to Current

- Acted as POC and monitored task budget and funding balances as well as analyzing and interpreting their weekly burn rates for the Mobile Deployable contract under UCS (United Command Suite)
- Assisted in managing, interpreting, and auditing projected and actual values of labor, services, and material in FY22/FY23
 CBRNE Spend Plans and their respective planned schedules (in relevance to the UCS Waterfall Chart)
- Compiled and organized quarterly and monthly deliverables detailing financial progress of CBRNE, J39, MSCOE, and MSNE to be delivered to sponsors
- Corresponded with Government Project Leads (GPLs) on a weekly basis about current tasking and budget for different efforts of the UCS contracts and anything concerning procurements/acquisitions and engineering changes
- Inputted Funding Identification and Funding Realignments into ATLAS as they corresponded with entries in the CBRNE SPs, TIDs Revisions, and the need to move funds from one project code to another

Financial Management Analyst | NAVAIR HQ | Patuxent River, MD | March 2021 to June 2022

- Edited and balanced the General Ledger and Document Tracker dealing with commitments, obligations, and expenditures in accordance to MISIL, InfoWarehouse, Navy ERP, and CRT for each respective partner nation
- Created Purchase Orders and modified funding documents with pullback or additional funding amendments
- Constructed and updated SPID numbers in CSPT, and reviewed and compared exported spreadsheets of SPID Entries and their Direct, Labor, and Travel costs
- Generated weekly ZRQIS0002/0003 and ZRCCC007 reports of Undistributed Labor Postings and budget expenditures for
 each project, billing structure, and funding document and calculated how many funds to increase their funding documents
 by to balance the postings

Accounting Clerk | Eagles Systems, Inc. | California, MD | February 2020 to February 2021

- Reviewed, investigated, and corrected errors in vouchers, invoices, and financial entries for accuracy and entered data into automated accounts payable approval system (Costpoint)
- Processed weekly employee payroll and payments received from customers while ensuring accuracy and timeliness
- Reconciled bank statement versus general ledger precisely and analyzed with aged A/P & A/R reports
- Compared material and expense budgets in project ledger with actual performance in the material tracker on a current and iob-to-date basis

EDUCATION

Candidate for Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (B.S.)

2023 - 2024

University Maryland Global Campus, Adelphi, MD

Anticipated Date: August, 2024

Bachelor of Science in Accounting (B.S.)
University Maryland Global Campus, Adelphi, MD

2019 - 2020

Dean's Honor List

CERTIFICATIONS

Deltek University Costpoint

U.S. DoD

Professional Costpoint Certification with Accounts Payable Exam

Active Secret Security Clearance

SKILLS

Technical:

- Enterprise-supported Database and Software
- Risk Management
- Levels I, II, & III DAWIA Training DoD Business Finance Management
- Data Warehousing and Entry
- Data Analysis and Data Trending Knowledge
- Advanced Information and Data Researcher
- Accounts Payable and Reconciliation, Financial Auditing
- MS Office Suite, Adobe, Google Workspace
- MS Visual Studio Code
- Power Pivot
- Rudimentary of Python and Java
- HTML, CSS, Javascript (React)
- Rudimentary of NPM and Git repositories
- Familiar with Qlik Sense, Spark, Jupyter Notebook, Power BI, and SQL Queries

Transferable:

- Effective and meticulous written and verbal communication skills
- Capable of working under pressure and fulfilling deadlines
- Anticipates obstacles and problems and offers workable solutions around the ramifications
- Ability to work independently and with a team
- Scrupulously vigilant about details
- Extensive knowledge of research methodology for key project issues
- Works cooperatively to identify and pinpoint areas of needed improvement
- Tactfully displays divergent and heuristic thinking
- Stimulates curiosity and widens intellectual horizons and inquisitiveness
- Outstanding skill of memorization
- Maintains a high degree of maturity and professionalism
- Highly efficient in analyzing and solving problems to the utmost accuracy and quality

REFERENCES

Veronica M. Johnson APEO(T) BFM

Phone: (240) 298-8194

Email: Veronica.m.Johnson.civ@navy.mail

Katherine P. Bell Director of Finance Phone: 301-863-2453

Email: kbell@eaglesystemsinc.com

Stephen Simeone

Instructor of Business: Accounting

Phone: 240-539-4186 Email: sfsimeone@csmd.edu

Lynda Johnson

Chief Executive Officer Phone: 301-863-2453

Email: ljohnson@eaglesystemsinc.com

Lorie Wathen

NAVAIR FMS Financial Management Analyst

Phone: 301-904-0825

Email: lorie.wathen@navy.mil

